rossstores.com 2019-09-29

# Privacy Policy - Ross Stores, Inc.

Ross Stores, Inc. (" **Ross** ," " **we** ," " **us** ") is concerned about online privacy issues and wants you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose your Personally Identifiable Information (as defined below). This Privacy Policy (the " **Policy** ") describes our practices in connection with Personally Identifiable Information that we collect through our web site located at <https://www.rossstores.com/> (the **"Site"** ). This Policy does not address our practices regarding information that we collect through any web site, or by any other means, other than through the Site; nor does this Policy govern the collection, use or disclosure of information by any of our affiliates (collectively, **"Affiliated Entities"** ) or by third parties.

By using the Site, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Policy. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Policy, please do not use the Site. We reserve the right to change this Policy without prior notice. You can determine when this Policy was last revised by referring to the "LAST UPDATED" legend at the top of this page. Any changes to our Policy will become effective upon our posting of the revised Policy on the Site. Use of the Site following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised Policy then in effect.

**Note Regarding the Use of the Site by Children:** The Site is not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and we request that such individuals do not provide Personally Identifiable Information through the Site.

### What Types of Information Does Ross Collect From Me?

Ross gathers two basic types of information through the Site: " **Personally Identifiable Information** " (or " **PII** ") and " **Non-Personally Identifiable Information** " (or " **Non-PII** "). Personally Identifiable Information is information that identifies you as an individual, or relates to an identifiable person, including: name, postal address, telephone number, email address, and credit or debit card number. Non-Personally Identifiable Information is aggregated information, demographic information, IP addresses and any other information that does not reveal your specific identity, or does not directly relate to an individual.

#### Personally Identifiable Information.

You do not have to provide PII to use the Site. However, in order for you to take advantage of particular opportunities provided through the Site (for example, to register for e-mail, to submit a job application or ask a question), we may require that you furnish PII. We collect PII from you through the Site, such as your name, postal address, telephone number or e-mail address, only when you voluntarily provide it to us.

We use a third-party payment service ("Payment Service") to collect payments made through the Site when purchasing a Ross gift card online. We also use a third-party service to collect online donations (“Donation Service”). If you wish to purchase a gift card or make a donation through the Site, you will be directed to a webpage that is hosted by the Payment Service (or the Payment Service’s service providers), or the Donation Service, and not by Ross (the "Payment Service Page" or the “Donation Service Page”). Any PII that you provide through the Payment Service Page or the Donation Service Page will be collected by the Payment Service or the Donation Service, and not by Ross, and will be subject to Payment Service's or Donation Service’s privacy policy, rather than this Policy. Ross has no control over, and shall not be responsible for, Payment Service’s or Donation Service’s use of information collected through the Payment Service Page or the Donation Service Page. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS POLICY DOES NOT ADDRESS THE COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION THROUGH THE PAYMENT SERVICE PAGE OR THE DONATION SERVICE PAGE, OR THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF PAYMENT SERVICE OR DONATION SERVICE.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

When you visit and interact with the Site, Ross and its third-party service providers may collect Non-PII (for example, a catalog of the Site pages you visit). Non-PII is generally collected through the Site from five different sources:

  1. server log files,
  2. environmental variables,
  3. cookies,
  4. pixel tags and other similar technologies, and
  5. information that you voluntarily provide to us.

#### Server Log Files.

Your Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). This number is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you visit the Site, along with the time(s) of your visit(s) and the page(s) that you visited. We and our service providers use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating Site usage levels, helping diagnose problems with the Site's servers, and administering the Site. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice on the Internet and is done automatically by many web sites. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address.

#### Environmental Variables.

We and our service providers may also collect certain environmental variables, such as your computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, OS version, Internet browser, and Internet browser version. These environmental variables are collected by most browsers, and can be used to optimize your experience on the Site.

#### Cookies.

We and our service providers may use “cookies” in connection with the Site. Cookies are data that a web server transfers to an individual's computer for recordkeeping and other purposes, including to facilitate users’ ongoing access to and use of a particular web site, as well as to understand how the site is used. Cookies are an industry standard used by most web sites; cookies do not cause damage to your computer systems or files. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies, or to be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer of a particular cookie, or cookies from a particular web site, to your computer. We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and other, similar technologies to collect and analyze information about Site use and report on activities and trends. This service may also collect information regarding the use of other websites. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. At this time we do not respond to browser do-not-track signals.

#### Pixel Tags.

We and our service providers may also use so-called "pixel tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs," or similar means in connection with Site pages and HTML-formatted e-mail messages to, among other things, track the actions of Site users and e-mail recipients, to determine the success of marketing campaigns and to compile aggregate statistics about Site usage and response rates.

#### Interest Based Advertising.

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding goods and services that may be of interest to you when you access and use our Site and other websites, apps or online services, based on information relating to your access and use of our Site and other websites, apps and services on any of your devices, as well as information received from third parties. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through the use of pixel tags). They may also use these technologies, along with information they collect about your online use, to recognize you across the devices you use, such as a mobile phone and a laptop. If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn how to opt out of it in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Privacy Policy, please visit <http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/>choices/. You may download the AppChoices app at [www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices) to opt out in mobile apps.

#### Information That You Voluntarily Provide.

Ross also collects Non-PII (e.g., your interests, your geographic location, etc.) when you voluntarily provide such information to us. Such information constitutes Non-PII because, unless combined with PII, it does not personally identify you or any other user. Additionally, we may aggregate PII in a manner such that the end-product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site, for example, by using PII to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code. Such aggregate information is considered Non-PII for purposes of this Policy.

### How Does Ross Use Information Collected From Me?

#### Personally Identifiable Information.

We may use PII about you in the following ways:

#### Fulfillment of Requests.

Ross may use PII about you to fulfill the purpose for which such PII was provided (e.g., to send newsletters to you or respond to your inquiries).

#### Administrative Communications.

From time to time, in our sole discretion, we may use PII about you to send to you important information regarding the Site, changes to our terms, conditions, and policies or other administrative information. Because this information may be important to your use of the Site, you may not opt-out of receiving such communications.

#### Other Communications.

From time to time, we may use PII about you to inform you of products, programs, services and promotions that we believe may be of interest to you. If you would prefer that we do not send electronic marketing messages to you, please see the "Opt-Out" section below.

#### Promotions.

We may operate sweepstakes, contests and similar promotions (collectively, "Promotions") through the Site. We typically ask you for certain PII when you enter and, if applicable, win a Promotion. You should carefully review the rules, if any, of each Promotion in which you participate through the Site, as they may contain additional important information about Ross's use of PII about you. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of PII about you conflict with this Policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall control.

#### Business Purposes.

We may also use PII about you for our general business purposes including but not limited to data analysis, audits, advertising and so forth.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

Because Non-PII does not personally identify you, we may use such information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. In addition, we reserve the right to share such Non PII, which does not personally identify you, with Affiliated Entities and other third parties, for any purpose. If we are required to treat Non-PII as PII under applicable law, then we may use and disclose it for the purposes for which we use and disclose PII as detailed in this Privacy Policy.

In some instances, we may combine Non-PII with PII (such as combining your name with your geographic location). If we do combine any Non-PII with PII, the combined information will be treated by us as PII hereunder as long as it is so combined.

### How Is Personally Identifiable Information Disclosed?

#### Third Party Service Providers.

We work with third parties who provide services including but not limited to data analysis, web hosting, managing our mailing lists, advertising, order fulfillment and other administrative purposes. We reserve the right to share PII about you with such third parties for the purpose of enabling these third parties to provide such services.

#### Promotions.

We reserve the right to share the PII you provide in connection with Promotions with third party sponsors of such Promotions (irrespective of whether such Promotions are hosted by us), or otherwise in accordance with the rules applicable to such Promotion. You should carefully review the rules, if any, of each Promotion in which you participate through the Site, as they may contain additional important information about a sponsor's or other third parties’ use of PII about you. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of PII about you conflict with this Policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall control.

#### Assignment.

We reserve the right to transfer any and all information that we collect from Site users to an Affiliated Entity or a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of Ross's business, assets or stock (including without limitation in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

#### Law enforcement; emergencies; compliance.

We reserve the right to use and disclose PII about you to others:

  1. as required or permitted under applicable law;
  2. to comply with legal process;
  3. to respond to governmental requests;
  4. to enforce our Terms of Service;
  5. to protect our operations or those of any Affiliated Entities;
  6. to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of dd's, the Affiliated Entities, you or others; and
  7. to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

### Other Important Notices Regarding Our Privacy Practices.

#### Third-Party Sites.

The Site may contain links to third-party web sites. These linked sites are not under Ross's control and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the contents of any such linked site, or any link contained in any linked site. We provide such links only as a convenience, and the inclusion of a link on the Site does not imply endorsement of the linked site by Ross or any Affiliated Entities. If you provide any PII through any such third-party web site, your transaction will occur on such third party's web site (not the Site) and the PII you provide will be collected by, and controlled by the privacy policy of, that third party. We recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices of any such third parties. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS POLICY DOES NOT ADDRESS THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTIES, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THE AFFILIATED ENTITIES.

#### Security.

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical, and administrative measures to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the PII under our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or data storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, although we strive to protect PII about you, we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us through or in connection with the Site or that is stored by us. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), you must immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us in accordance with the Section called “Contacting Us" below (note that if you choose to notify us via physical mail, this will delay the time it takes for us to respond to the problem). Ross will never ask for PII in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail.

#### Opt-Out.

If you do not wish to receive marketing-related e-mails from us, you may opt-out by following the instructions contained in each such e-mail.

#### Jurisdictional Issues.

The Site is controlled and operated by Ross from the United States, and is not intended to subject Ross or any Affiliated Entity to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. Your PII may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and, by using the Site, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside your country of residence, including the United States, which may have data protection rules that are different from those of your country.

**Nevada Residents as Covered by Nevada Privacy Law.**

Ross does not sell Covered Information as defined under Nevada law.  If you would like to make a further inquiry regarding the selling of your Covered Information, as defined under Nevada law, please contact us by using the form located on the Contact Us page using the subject line “Nevada Privacy Request”.

#### Contacting Us.

If you have any questions regarding this Policy, please contact us by using the form located on the Contact Us page.
